ここには まだ来ていない。
They haven't been here yet.
Not yet, huh?
まだか…。
動きがあるまで ここを監視する。
We'll monitor the area here
until there's movement!
うっ！ し… 知らねえ！
I-I don't know...
No way would I tell you even if I did.
知ってたとしても
言うわけがねえ！
That's what he says.
Should we kill him?
…だとよ。 やっちまうか？
拷問なら
イビキにでも任せておけばいい。
We should leave the torture to Ibiki.
No signs of the Akatsuki, after all.
やっぱり
暁がいた形跡は ないよ。
Same here.
こっちも同じ。 ここ数日
人の出入りした形跡がない。
It doesn't look like anyone's been
through here for several days...
まだ ここに来てないのは確かね。
I think it's certain
they haven't been here yet.
What's the plan, Aoba?
どうする？ アオバ。
うっ…！
他の４つの換金所へ向かった
部隊からの➡
There are still no requests for backup
from the units that went to
the other four Collection Offices.
バックアップ要請は まだない。
(ライドウ)ならば 暁との接触は
まだということか…。
Which means there's still been
no contact with the Akatsuki, huh?
Well, I don't know about that.
いや どうかな…
すでに交戦中かもしれん。
They might already be in
the middle of a fight right now.
Don't worry.
心配するな。 アスマさんの部隊が
接触したのなら 最も安心だ。
It'd be reassuring if Asuma's unit
were to make contact with the Akatsuki.
You guys know of his strength
better than anyone, right?
あの人の強さは お前たちが
いちばんよく知っているだろう？
That's right.
そうですよね。
うん。 シカマルもいるしね。
Yeah, and Shikamaru's with him, too.
All right! Let's head out and
work out another strategy.
よし！ 一度 外へ出て
作戦を立て直そう。
行くぞ。
Let's go!
いま一度
すべての情報を整理するとだ➡
Let's sort out all the information
we have right now.
The Akatsuki have headed for
one of the five Collection Offices.
暁は ５つのうちの
いずれかの換金所へ向かった。
There have been no requests
for backup from the other four.
他 ４つからのバックアップ要請は ない。
And they haven't been to
this Collection Office, yet.
そして
この換金所へは まだ来ていない。
ということは…。
That means...
Right.
There's a chance
まだ この換金所へ向かってる
可能性もあるってことだな。
they might still be heading for
this Collection Office.
そういうことだ。
待ち伏せして暁を… 獲る！
That's about the size of it.
We'll lie in wait and grab them.
現段階で考えられる
敵の行動パターンは以上だ。
These are all the possible patterns of
action for the enemy at this stage.
先ほどの作戦どおり
各自 持ち場につけ！
All of you take up positions and
wait as devised earlier!
Yes, sir!
(忍たち)ハッ！
暁… どこに行った!?
Where'd the Akatsuki go?
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Climbing
Silver
角都 遅かったな。
Took you long enough, Kakuzu!
おせえよ。
Too slow.
まずは１人。
We got one to start.
あぁ～ いってえ… 何だ？ テメエら。
That hurts...
What's with you jerks?
どういうことだ？
急所を貫いたのに…。
What's the meaning of this?
We pierced his vital spots.
グリグリすんなぁ！
Don't push it in deeper like that!
いてえんだよ コラ！
Hey, that hurts!
コイツ… 不死身か？
Is this guy... immortal?
見りゃ わかんだろ！
で… テメエら 何もんだ？
Isn't it obvious?
So... who're you guys?
ん？ そのマーク。
たしか 守護人なんたらの…。
That mark.
If I remember correctly, it's from
the Guardian Shinobi or something...
はぁ～ マジかよ…➡
Are you kidding me?
Do I have to go back inside that
smelly Collection Office again?
あんな くせえ換金所に
また行かなきゃなんねえのかよ。
Chiriku...
《地陸…》
(アスマ)オレたちは 木ノ葉の忍だ。
We're Hidden Leaf Shinobi.
お前ら暁を拘束 または
抹殺するよう 命を受けてきた。
We've been ordered to either
capture or eliminate you Akatsuki.
お前ら暁は ツーマンセルで行動する。
まずは１人を片づけてから➡
Akatsuki operate in teams of two.
Our intention was to take down
one of you first
もう一方を
拘束するつもりだったが…。
and then capture the other.
さすがに
いい能力を 持ってやがる。
But you're pretty tough,
as was expected.
《これが暁か…
なんて ふざけた能力だ！
So this is the Akatsuki, huh?
What insane ability.
これじゃ 影縫いも…》
My Shadow Sewing probably won't...
クッ… フフッ。
テメエら 狙う順番を間違えたな。
You jerks went after us
in the wrong order.
もう１人は どこだ？
Where's the other one?
んっ？
The Jutsu's broken!
術が はずれた！
コテツ イズモ 下がれ!!
Kotetsu, Izumo, get back!
やはり あの真ん中の…
珍しくカネに縁があったな 飛段。
Sure enough, the guy in the middle...
This is a first, you being interested
in money, Hidan.
Kakuzu...
角都… テメエは手を出すな。
コイツらは オレの儀式用だ。
You stay out of this.
I'm going to use these guys for my ritual.
カネは テメエにやる。
I'll give you the money.
Kakuzu... and Hidan, huh?
《角都… それから 飛段か…》
Very well... But don't get careless.
You'll die.
それなら いいだろう…
ただ気を抜くな… 死ぬぞ。
(飛段)だから…
それを オレに言うかよ。
I told you.
Don't give me that.
If they could  kill me,
I'd want them to.
(飛段)殺せるもんなら
殺してほしいぜ。
Well... I guess it's impossible, huh?!
まぁ… ムリかぁ!?
What's he going to do
with that diagram?
《何のつもりだ？
あの図形…》
オレが突っ込む。
I'll charge him.
Shikamaru, exploit an opening
スキをついて 不死身男を
影縫いで縛れ シカマル。
and restrain the immortal guy
with your Shadow Sewing.
It doesn't have to be for long.
少しの時間でいい。
すぐに 首をはねて動きを止める。
I'll cut his head off immediately
and stop his movements.
That's too risky.
This isn't like you.
それじゃ リスクが高すぎっすよ。
アンタらしくない…。
私も一緒に…。
I should go with you.
わからないのか！
それが 今打てる最善の手だ!!
Don't you get it?!
That's the best thing we can do right now!
《アスマのこんな顔 初めて見るぜ》
I've never seen Asuma
look like this before.
ヤツらは オレより はるかに強い…。
These guys are way
stronger than me.
Izumo, Kotetsu,
you guys back up Shikamaru
イズモ コテツ。
お前らは もう片方の暁に
気を配りつつ シカマルの護衛だ。
while keeping an eye on
the other Akatsuki guy.
If we know what they're capable of,
then all the more reason
相手の力が わかっているなら
なおさら…➡
we should pull out for now
and plan a strategy.
ここは いったん
退いて作戦を立てるのが…。
They won't let us get away
that easily.
アイツら相手に 簡単に
退かせてもらえると思うな。
If we try to escape
without putting up a fight,
戦意なく逃げようものなら
オレたちは全滅する。
we'll be completely wiped out...
そうなれば 木ノ葉のリスクは
さらに高まる。
If that happens,
the Hidden Leaf
will be in even greater danger.
It's like sending in an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
敵陣突破の尖兵だ。
Sometimes you have to be able
to make a move like that.
たまには こういう指し方も
できないとな。
I thought you didn't like moves like that.
Just like me...
((そういう指し方
嫌いじゃなかったっすか？
オレと同じで…。
上手相手に
玉を守るためには➡
Sacrifice is required in order
to protect the king
when your opponent
is extremely skilled.
(犠牲もやむなし ってヤツだ))
《まさか アスマのヤツ
自分を犠牲にして…。
Don't tell me he's going
to sacrifice himself.
一人は能力不明の馬鹿力➡
One of them has great physical strength
with unknown abilities.
One of them is immortal.
一人は不死身…。
Indeed, we don't
stand much of a chance.
確かに オレたちには 分が悪い。
Even so, I can't believe Asuma would
use himself as a sacrificial piece.
だからって
アスマが犠牲駒になんて…》
Shogi?
What a pain...
((シカマル : 将棋？ 面倒くせえな…。
I know you're lazy.
お前が 面倒くさがりなのは
知ってるよ。
And I also know
that you're good at
だから
面倒なのを避けるために➡
planning strategies
for avoiding trouble.
作戦を立てるのが
得意だってこともな。
In Shogi, you can create
a variety of situations
将棋はな… いろんな駒の
個性を活かすことで➡
by utilizing the individual characteristics
of the various pieces.
さまざまな局面を
作り出すことができる。
It's the perfect game
for a person like you
お前のように 作戦を考えるのが
得意なヤツには➡
who's good at
coming up with strategies.
うってつけのゲームだよ。
You should be able to
figure out
ルールは だいたい
この本を読めばわかる。
most of the rules
if you read this book.
あとは やりながらだな。
The rest you'll pick up as you play.
It's a pain, but I should have it
down in ten minutes.
面倒くせえけど こんなの
10分ありゃ 完璧っすよ。
ま… 負けた…。
I-I lost...
手抜かなくて
いいっすよ マジで。
You don't have to go easy on me...
Seriously.
But I can't believe you'd go
with the Climbing Silver.
しかし 棒銀とはな。
It was in this book.
(シカマル)この本に
書いてあったんすよ。
It said to use an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
敵陣突破の尖兵だってね。
そんなに 負けたのが
悔しかったっすか？
Are you that upset you lost?
No. Using advance units
as sacrificial pieces
いや… 犠牲駒を使った
敵陣突破の尖兵か。
to break through enemy lines, huh?
It seems like the rational kind of idea
you would come up with...
お前らしい
合理的な考えかもしれんが➡
But I don't really like it.
オレは あんまし
好きじゃねえんだよ。
(シカマル)ゲームだぜ？
It's just a game.
I guess.
But the Climbing Silver piece,
まぁね。
だが 敵陣を切り崩し➡
while inflicting a lot of damage
and undermining the enemy line,
大ダメージを与えた棒銀は
犠牲駒となる。
ends up becoming a sacrificial piece.
Certainly taking each other's pieces
is a natural part of the game.
もちろん 駒のやりとりは
当然だが➡
But to consider throwing away
your pieces to be by-the-book...
犠牲駒を全面に打ち出した
この定石…。
オレは そこまで
割り切れないってことさ。
I guess
I'm not quite satisfied with that.
I'm not as rational
as you say I am.
オレだって 言うほど
合理的じゃねえよ。
(アスマ)フッ もう一番やるか。
Shall we play again?
This time I'll take it nice and slow,
(シカマル)今度は じっくり
棒銀なんて使わねえでな))
and I won't use the Climbing Silver.
Breaking through enemy lines...
《敵陣突破…。
Which means these enemies
are so powerful,
犠牲駒もやむなしと
思わせるほどの敵ってことか。
he thinks using sacrificial pieces
is inevitable, huh?
Indeed, we Chunin
would not be pieces
確かに
オレたち中忍じゃ➡
that could put pressure
on these guys.
ヤツらに 圧力と
なるような駒にゃならねえ》
Furthermore, Asuma would be
at an overwhelming disadvantage
《それどころか オレたちを
守りながら戦うとなれば➡
if he had to fight while protecting us.
圧倒的に不利。
We could very well be completely
wiped out as Asuma said.
アスマの言うとおり 全滅もありえる。
What's the best move?
何か最善の手は…。
They are major pieces,
no doubt about it.
ヤツらは 間違いなく 大駒だ。
Bait is necessary to
capture a major piece.
大駒をとらえるには エサが必要だ。
We need bait that's big enough
to make them think
大駒の代償もやむなしと
思えるほどの➡
it's an unavoidable price to pay
for the capture of a major piece.
最善の手と思えるエサが…。
We're not good enough...
to be bait.
オレたちじゃ
そのエサとしては 役不足。
If we have to fight with the pieces
we have available to us now...
今の持ち駒で
使える戦力となると…》
The Climbing Silver doesn't suit you.
棒銀なんて アンタには向いてない。
フフ… ただの捨て駒には
ならねえよ。
I won't be a mere sacrificial piece.
I've got you with me, after all.
お前がいるんだからな。
《情けねえ…。
エサにも圧力にもならねえが➡
How pathetic...
I can't be the bait and I can't put
pressure on the enemy.
But I'll divert the major pieces
like crazy.
オレが 大駒を牽制しまくってやる》
Are you done with
your little strategy session?
(飛段)作戦会議は終わったか？
イテテ…。
グサグサ刺しやがって
いてえな テメエら。
Getting cut up like that
hurts like hell, you jerks.
Divine justice will be handed down
to you jerks
人の痛みを知らねえ クソ野郎には
神の裁きが下るぜ。
who know nothing of the pain of others.
ケッ！ いい武器
持ってんじゃねえか！
You've got a nice weapon there!
アスマ！
Asuma!
クソッ！ 届け！
Damn it! Reach!
《フッ アイツをくらったら
終わっちまうからな》
I'm finished if I get hit by that.
《何度でも折ってやる》
I'll break you over and over again.
チッ！
《シカマル それでいい。
Shikamaru... That's fine.
アイツは 影縫いを警戒しながら
戦わなければならない。
He has to fight while watching out
for your Shadow Sewing.
こっちが有利だ》
I have the advantage.
クソ…。
Damn it!
《確かに オレの影縫いの攻撃が➡
Indeed, my Shadow Sewing attack
is creating
アスマにとって
有利な戦いを生み出す。
an advantageous battle for Asuma.
基本的には 間違っちゃいない。
Essentially, we're not mistaken...
But there's no point to
having an advantage in this fight.
だけどよ
戦いが有利だろうが 意味がねえ。
アイツは不死身。 こっちは
命もチャクラにも限りがある。
He's immortal,
and we have a limit to
our Chakra and our lives.
捕まえなきゃ
こっちの戦いは始まらねえ。
The real battle won't begin
until I grab him.
今は考えてるヒマはねえ》
I don't have the time to think now.
させるかっ！
I don't think so!
Oh no!
しまった！
この構えは…！
That stance!
うおっ！
地陸の術は どうだ？
How's Chiriku's Jutsu?
Naturally, Chiriku's is much
more impressive than mine, though.
もっとも 地陸のは
もっとすごいがな。
クソッ！
Damn it!
Hidan! Don't underestimate them.
飛段 油断するな。
Keep quiet!
うるせえな。
黙って見てろよ 角都。
Just shut up and watch, Kakuzu.
うまい！
Nice!
《さすが この２人は
息が合っている》
As one would expect,
the two of them are in synch.
チッ！
It appears he really is going
to stay out of this.
《どうやら アイツは
本当に 手を出してこねえようだ。
といって
信用するわけにもいかねえが》
Even so, we can't trust him to do that.
さっきのは
惜しかったぞ シカマル。
You almost got him just now, Shikamaru.
More importantly...
んなことより ちょっと
援護してもらえねえっすかね？
Could you back me up?
ケッ！ おめえら 必死すぎなんだよ。
You guys are too desperate.
Atheists always try to escape death
with the most efficient approach.
無神論者どもは
いちばん効率のいい方法で➡
命をとりにくる！
見え見えなんだよ!!
It's totally obvious!
《お前の戦いは
遊びが多すぎだがな》
You play around too much
when you fight.
Now!
《今だ！》
This time you've got nowhere to run.
今度は 逃げ場ねえぜ！
なら よけねえよ。
Then I won't dodge!
チッ… 不死身野郎め！
Immortal jerk!
先に ザコのほうから
片付けてやろうか！
I guess I'll take care of the small fries first.
《しまった！》
Oh no!
お前の相手は オレだ!!
I'm your opponent!
アスマ隊長！
Captain Asuma!
《コンビネーション技も ピンポイント攻撃も
当たらないなら…》
If combo and pinpoint attacks won't hit...
ヘヘッ…。
《火遁 灰積焼!!》
Burning Ash!
(飛段)フン…。
《動きを止めただと…？》
He stopped his movements?
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
Next Episode
What's happening?
(シズネ)不公平よ！ 不公平！
He's the one who was nailed by the Jutsu?
あなたは いいわよね。
スタイルはいいし 美人だし。
Why's the captain...?!
Don't tell me... this is...!
(紅)ちょっと飲みすぎよ。
Hey, did you figure something out, Shikamaru?
で どうなの？
え？
I don't know what kind of approach
he used.
アスマさんのことよ！
But his and Asuma's body
might be connected
さぁ どうかしら…。
with some kind of mechanism.
Say what?!
あっ 赤くなった！
もう…。
Connected? What does that mean?!
(シズネ)あぁ うらやましい！
Next time: "The Judgment"
私なんか 一日じゅう
綱手様と一緒だからね。
The Judgment
(紅)あら
立派な仕事じゃない。
でもね
一緒に旅してたときも…。
It's not fair!
出会う男ときたら
こ～んなのばっかり！
You're so lucky.
You've got a great body
and you're beautiful.
あ～もう このままじゃ
綱手様みたいに いき遅れちゃう！
I think you've had
too much to drink.
— So? How is he?
— Huh?
あ… ちょっと
それくらいにしといたほうが…。
I'm talking about Asumal
大丈夫！ 全然酔ってないから。
Who knows?
You're blushing.
(紅)いや そうじゃなくて…。
(綱手)シズネ!!
Good grief.
Oh, man!
I really envy you.
I'm stuck with Tsunade-sama
all day long, you see.
今の話の続き
ゆっくり聞かせてもらおうか。
Oh, it's fine work.
(シズネ)あひ～～っ!!
But even when we travel together,
the guys we meet are always like this!
Oh! At this rate, I'll wind up single forever
just like Tsunade-sama!
I think you'd better stop there.
It's okay.
I'm not drunk at all.
That's not what I mean...
Shizune!
I would very much like to hear
the rest of what you have to say.